<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tools on KryoLogs</title><link>https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/tools/</link><description>Recent content in Tools on KryoLogs</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 14:57:09 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>VCSim</title><link>https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/tools/vcsim/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 14:57:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/tools/vcsim/</guid><description>Overview linkThis package implements a vSphere Web Services (SOAP) SDK endpoint intended for testing consumers of the API. While the mock framework is written in the Go language, it can be used by any language that can talk to the vSphere API.
See their github for more info.
Usage linkTo run vcsim using docker run the following:
docker run -p 8989:8989 vmware/vcsim:latest To test functionality of the container you can run the following command.</description></item><item><title>PowerCLI</title><link>https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/tools/powercli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 14:56:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/tools/powercli/</guid><description>Overview linkVmware PowerCLI is a Powershell module used interact with vCenter amd vSphere APIs. This allows for simple automation of mundane, redundant tasks, like inventorying servers.
Installation linkTo install PowerCLI open up a powershell window and run the following command.
Install-Module VMware.PowerCLI -Scope CurrentUser -AllowClobber Using PowerCLI linkGetting connected to your cluster can be performed with one command.
Connect-ViServer &amp;lt;vcenter.domain.com&amp;gt; -Credentials $(Get-Credentials) -Force Get a list of your clusters, hosts, and vms.</description></item><item><title>Minikube</title><link>https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/tools/minikube/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 14:56:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/tools/minikube/</guid><description>Overview linkMinikube is local Kubernetes, focusing on making it easy to learn and develop for Kubernetes. All you need is Docker (or similarly compatible) container or a Virtual Machine environment, and Kubernetes is a single command away: minikube start.
Installation link curl -LO https://storage.googleapis.com/minikube/releases/latest/minikube-linux-amd64 sudo install minikube-linux-amd64 /usr/local/bin/minikube Uninstallation link sudo rm /usr/local/bin/minikube Customize Cluster linkGet configurable items using:
minikube config --help To set configuration properties:
minikube config set &amp;lt;property&amp;gt; &amp;lt;value&amp;gt; To get current configuration:</description></item></channel></rss>