<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CDK on KryoLogs</title><link>https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/aws/cdk/</link><description>Recent content in CDK on KryoLogs</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 20:56:51 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/aws/cdk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS CDK</title><link>https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/aws/cdk/aws-cdk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 08:41:52 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/aws/cdk/aws-cdk/</guid><description>Getting Started linkWhat is the CDK linkThe AWS Cloud Development Kit (AWS CDK) is an open-source software development framework for defining cloud infrastructure in code and provisioning it through AWS CloudFormation.
The AWS CDK consists of two primary parts:
AWS CDK Construct Library – A collection of pre-written modular and reusable pieces of code, called constructs, that you can use, modify, and integrate to develop your infrastructure quickly. The goal of the AWS CDK Construct Library is to reduce the complexity required to define and integrate AWS services together when building applications on AWS.</description></item><item><title>Building Your First CDK Application</title><link>https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/aws/cdk/aws-cdk-first-app-go/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 20:56:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://kalebhawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/docs/aws/cdk/aws-cdk-first-app-go/</guid><description>Building a CDK Application with Go linkIn this tutorial we will look at how to build a simple app that creates a single S3 bucket using Go.
For more detail reference the AWS Documentation. Their documentation also shows you how to do the same thing in other languages like Python.
Initialize New Application link # You can substitute go for whatever language. cdk init app --language go # Install the required Go modules go get Build the Application linkIn most programming environments, you build or compile code after making changes.</description></item></channel></rss>