<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vmware on KryoLogs</title><link>https://KalebHawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/tags/vmware/</link><description>Recent content in vmware on KryoLogs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://KalebHawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/tags/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Red Hat - 8.5 VMWare Template</title><link>https://KalebHawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/posts/linux/redhat/vmware-template/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://KalebHawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/posts/linux/redhat/vmware-template/</guid><description>Prerequisites Create the Virtual Machine Prepare for Red Hat Installation Red Hat Installation Template Configuration Prerequisites Access to Red Hat&amp;rsquo;s access portal to download the Red Hat ISO. An active Red Hat Enterprise Linux subscription. Create the Virtual Machine Sign into vCenter.
Right-click the cluster you want to create the virtual machine on.
Select New Virtual Machine.
Set the name and select a folder to place the template in.</description></item><item><title>Setup vcsim</title><link>https://KalebHawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/posts/tools/vcsim/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://KalebHawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/posts/tools/vcsim/</guid><description>Overview Usage Overview This package implements a vSphere Web Services (SOAP) SDK endpoint intended for testing consumers of the API. While the mock framework is written in the Go language, it can be used by any language that can talk to the vSphere API.
See their github for more info.
Usage To run vcsim using docker run the following:
docker run -p 8989:8989 vmware/vcsim:latest To test functionality of the container you can run the following command.</description></item><item><title>Vmware PowerCLI</title><link>https://KalebHawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/posts/tools/powercli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://KalebHawkins.github.io/KryoLogs/posts/tools/powercli/</guid><description>Overview Installation Using PowerCLI Overview Vmware PowerCLI is a Powershell module used interact with vCenter amd vSphere APIs. This allows for simple automation of mundane, redundant tasks, like inventorying servers.
Installation To install PowerCLI open up a powershell window and run the following command.
Install-Module VMware.PowerCLI -Scope CurrentUser -AllowClobber Using PowerCLI Getting connected to your cluster can be performed with one command.
Connect-ViServer &amp;lt;vcenter.domain.com&amp;gt; -Credentials $(Get-Credentials) -Force Get a list of your clusters, hosts, and vms.</description></item></channel></rss>